

Profile

I am a Software Engineer holding a **Bachelor** and a **Master** in **Computer Science** and being professionally active in this field since 2008. In my professional work, I focused mainly on **Web Development**, **Backend** as well as **Frontend**. In the last 6 years, I have been also working as a **Technical Consultant**, offering implementation and consulting services to different clients, most of them being in Germany.

I am an Oracle Certified Professional Java SE 8 Programmer and I enjoy learning new things and taking on new endeavours. A big part of my spare time I dedicate to expanding my knowledge, which is why I continuously attend various courses and programs offered by online learning platforms like Coursera, Edx, JetBrains Academy, Udacity or Udemy. When time allows it, I also attend and present at technical conferences.

Education

Master of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara, Romania

2008 - 2010

Master of Science in Informatics with a focus on Artificial Intelligence and Distributed Computing

Grade: 9 of 10

Bachelor of Science in Informatics, West University of Timişoara, Timişoara, Romania

2004 — 2008

Bachelor of Science in Informatics / Computer Science

Grade: 9.67 of 10 (ranked 7 of 95 graduates)

Employment History

Lead Software Developer at IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg

September 2019 — May 2020

I was the lead developer of one of the two agile development teams working on a web application.

Tech/Tools Stack: Java, Java EE, JUnit, TDD, Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Git, Jenkins, Docker, Linux, Oracle Database, H2, SQL, Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Oracle WebLogic Server, Payara Server, OpenAPI Specification, Domain-Driven Design

Senior Technical Consultant at virtual7 GmbH, Nürnberg

February 2019 — June 2020

Details

Nürnberg, Germany flore.vlad@gmail.com

Date of birth

15.11.1985

Nationality

Romanian

Links

Blog Linkedin GitHub

Skills

Java

Full Stack Development

Web Development

Angular

Computer Programming

Software Craftsmanship

Clean Code

Test Driven Development

Spring Framework

Spring Boot

RESTful WebServices

Git

GitHub

Leadership and Teamwork

DevOps

Docker

Ansible

JavaScript

After having worked for the Romanian branch, I switched over to the German company, where I continued working mostly for German clients, on-site. Besides that, I also held a couple of presentations (see Conferences section).

Full Stack Developer at Bundesamt für Migration und Flüchtlinge (BAMF), Nürnberg

May 2018 — September 2019

I was one of the full stack developers of an agile team working on a web application. Besides the developing tasks, I also handled Operational ones and assisted with deployment activities.

Tech/Tools Stack: Java, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, JUnit, Angular, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Git, Upsource, Jenkins, Ansible, Linux, Oracle Database, H2, SQL, Jira, Confluence

Software Developer at IT-Systemhaus der Bundesagentur für Arbeit, Nürnberg

May 2014 — March 2018

I was one of the developers of an agile team working on the services and the content management system of the client's website.

Tech/Tools Stack: Java, Java EE, Oracle WebCenter Content, Oracle Database, SQL, Oracle WebLogic Server, Linux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, Jenkins, Jira, Confluence

Senior Technical Consultant at virtual7 Romania, Nürnberg

May 2014 — February 2019

During this time I mostly worked with clients from Germany in their offices providing implementation and consultancy services as needed. Besides this, I also help a couple of presentations (see Conferences section) and worked on internal projects. For more details please see the above positions.

Software Developer at virtual7 Romania, Timişoara

February 2008 — May 2014

In this time I worked as a developer, in different projects, internal and external, in collaboration with other developers, either from the Romanian office or from the German one.

Tech Stack: Java, Java EE, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Oracle Database, SQL, Oracle WebCenter Content, Oracle WebLogic Server

Courses

Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python, edX (MITx)

August 2020 — October 2020

Core Spring Training, VMware (Pivotal)

March 2020 — March 2020

Software Design and Architecture Specialization, Coursera (University of Alberta)

November 2019 — June 2020

HTML & CSS

Bootstrap

OpenAPI Specification

SQL

AWS Lambda

Kotlin

Python

Microservices

Domain-Driven Design

Languages

English

German

Romanian

Hobbies

Travelling, Reading, Learning, Swimming

Python for Everybody Specialization, Coursera (University of Michigan)

November 2019 — December 2019

Version Control with Git, Coursera (Atlassian)

July 2019 — July 2019

Certifications

Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

June 2020 — June 2020

Certificate

Software Design and Architecture, online

June 2020 — June 2020

Certificate

Python for Everybody, online

January 2020 — January 2020

Certificate

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer, online

May 2019 — May 2019

Certificate

◄ References

References available upon request

Conferences

virtual7 GmbH, Freiburg

2019 - 2019

Online Presentation

virtual7 GmbH, Heidelberg

2018 — 2018

PDF Presentation

DOAG, Nürnberg

2017 - 2017

PDF Manuscript

PDF Presentation

DOAG, Nürnberg

2015 — 2015

PDF Manuscript

PDF Presentation

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

May 29th, 2020

To Whom It May Concern,

It is with great pleasure that I am writing this recommendation letter for Mr. Vlad Flore. I have known Mr. Vlad Flore on a professional level for two years now. During this time, I found him to be detail oriented and a solid and dependable professional. He would strive to understand the background and objectives regarding his assignments and ensure that they get done on time.

He is very proactive, approaches tasks with the right priority, does not need supervision but seeks help when needed. He communicates well and is very collaborative, he loves to learn and teach.

Mr. Vlad Flore has been working at virtual7 since 2008, when he joined the company as a young talent. Since then he has continued to grow and develop and has never stopped being curious and interested in everything that is new in the IT market, and now he's became a senior technical consultant very appreciated in his area of expertise.

Mr. Flore also held many presentations, internal and external, participated in trainings, internal and external and specialized in various fields, also obtaining several certifications. As external presentations I would like to mention that he held twice a conference, in 2015 and 2017 at DOAG (Deutsche Oracle-Anwendergruppe).

He worked on various projects, with different technologies, mainly with Java and Oracle WebCenter Content (Content Management System from Oracle).



virtual7 Romania S.R.L.
Piata Consiliul Europei, Nr. 2E
United Business Center 3, Timis
J35/3070/2004
RO 16876814
Timisoara, Romania
Tel: 004 0787 539 359

After 2014 Mr. Vlad Flore, started to work as a detachment in Germany which taught him to work in an international and multicultural environment.

In all these 11 years of collaboration in Romania, Mr. Vlad Flore proved to be a great colleague, a perfect professional, a person you could always rely on.

He has visited and worked with colleagues from different backgrounds in different countries and is very approachable. He is a natural problem solver. I highly recommend him and i believe that he will be a big asset to any team he works with. I wish him all the best.

Sincerely,

Catalina Hritcu

HR Business Partner

virtual7 Romania S.R.L.